hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft now
you're probably immediately wondering
why has he changed his skin again what's
going on yep i'm wearing a bow tie and a
suit because
i am
poor basically on the hermitcraft i have
no diamonds whatsoever i've spent my
last one i've got a bit of lapis but
nothing really of much value anymore so
i've spent all my money and i spent the
last of it getting this suit made so
basically
i need to make some money now
fortunately i have my money making
scheme right here with the did you die
boxes now i'm actually going to have to
sell one of these in order to continue
investing so i haven't quite finished
making them but i want to show you how
valuable these are look at this i think
i've kitted it out with just about
everything you might need now i want to
point out that even if i didn't take any
profit whatsoever the amount of diamonds
you need to get all this would be about
75 diamonds but that's without all of
the enchantments without all of the
books without all of the tens of
hundreds of trips up to the pigman farm
to kill these guys
like it doesn't include any of that so
75 diamonds base price that's then got
to include the hours i've spent
enchanting them and getting xp
so i'm not entirely sure how much i
should sell them for maybe definitely
over two stacks i think two stacks
minimum but i'm not entirely sure so
basically we're gonna go and see if we
can sell them now
we need someone
that dies a lot on the server that isn't
me and has lots of diamonds themselves
and there's one person that happens to
be online this very second
good times with scar
who has actually died more than me i
think i said uh
i said scar do you ever do you have a
sec to meet up i have an investment
opportunity and he said
yes come on over sweet okay so
fortunately scott i'm i'm trying to jump
without any lytra i feel like mumbo
right now let's pop on my stuff
and we'll go over to scar fortunately
for me scar
lives right next door which is amazing
because i rarely actually see him and oh
my goodness look at this this was just
his island full of shulker boxes
hello scar
hello green welcome aboard the uss
investment this is where all the
transactions here at paradise will take
place
okay oh my gosh you have a giant bowtie
oh yeah oh yeah okay so right yeah are
you ready for this because i'm about to
give you my sales pitch
oh i love sales pitches but that bow tie
is like not just a normal bow tie that
is a ginormous bow tie i mean you've got
to trust a guy with a giant bow tie
right which is it's part of it's part of
my thing you know are you ready for my
pitch
yeah pitch pitch me well first of all
i'm a i'm a door to door salesman so
here's the door
i'm gonna have to knock
hold on hold on let me get the let me
get my cat out of the way
okay
all right hello
uh hello sir um i have a couple of
questions for you if you uh if you would
indulge me with uh i don't answer my
door i'm sorry
go away
i don't answer my door in real life
forget the door
forget forget the door
can i have a couple of q have a couple
of minutes of your time sir please
i don't even answer my phone
i'm going to humor you because of the
bow tie
i knew it i knew the bowtie did this
okay i've got you how many times on the
server have you died oh it's nice that
you asked i just learned this i have
died 185 times and i am the undisputed
grand champion of death here on the
server and i'm proud of it wow you're
proud of that actually
no that's sad well i think i might have
a product
that interests you okay so what i have
here is a box full of goodies but not
just any goodies
the kind of goodies that you need in a
pinch when you've when you've died 188
times and you've got to go and collect
your stuff 188 times or maybe you've
even lost your stuff 188 times
this box is your savior it's a fully
enchanted set of tools and armor along
with elytra food rockets and an ender
chest
in case you die this is the greens did
you die box
how much
oh how much you are you sold you sold me
you sold me you have no idea korean the
pain causes a man when he dies in the
minutes of a recording or a stream the
shame it is brought upon him when he has
nothing to his name he walks amongst the
ground like a peasant without his wings
okay um
tell me tell me let's see here i can
even throw in this i can even throw in
an elder guardian head i'm all in here
well i guess i could give you a little
discount because of the elder guardian
head you know you know i'm a sucker for
those those uh player heads there um i
think maybe um uh three stacks oh wait
this is a private mail sorry sorry sorry
you know i was just um
i think three stacks of diamonds sounds
pretty fair what do you what do you
think um how much did you say do you say
11 diamonds no no no no um three three
stacks and
i'll leave i've even thrown in some puns
for you okay you know if you check out
the axe if you check out the axe it's
you know accidents happen
you know come on
okay okay i see
you you sold me that you named the tools
because that's extra experience points
that's extra time yeah yeah yeah all
right here you go oh yes we have a
second
and three
and and the playerhead yes
you know let's not beat around the bush
i've seen your wallet
where did you get so many diamonds
yes well in concor i mean we we may or
may not have you know profited from a
war i mean
but
and uh what else did i make money from
pretty much the pretty much war in
cherry is pretty much it oh boy you just
gave me three stacks of diamonds for
that and i'm still dirt poor competing
all right my dude thank you so much i'll
uh if you die and you need another box
you know where to find me
and probably a fifty percent discount
after first purchase okay all right
great all right yep thank you good
agreements good luck sell the rich stay
rich
that sale was surprisingly easy and it
means that i now have three more stacks
of diamonds to invest straight back into
the did you die boxes you can kind of
see that these did you die boxes are
going to sell quite well i i mean i have
to basically target the people that have
died a lot so right let's get changed
out of this salesman now on to the next
thing that i need to do i have basically
organized to meet up with iskal for our
very first architect meeting now
unfortunately mumbo could not make it
however i have got together with him and
we are going to discuss our plans i've
got my suit on as always when we're
having these kinds of meetings and i've
told him to meet me in the infinity room
which i believe he is yeah you can see
him look again little escalad85 let's
hop down
hello
well well well
someone's looking like a little lime
i i figured for the occasion i have to
step up my attire rightfully so i i
wasn't expecting this this looks good
anyway so you wanted to have a little
meeting here um actually this is mumbo's
chair
all right and that's my chair uh i think
when we invited you we didn't actually
think this through all the way so what
we're gonna do
is we're just gonna give you a little
we'll give you a little stall they are
that's that's your chair you want a big
chair you gotta earn one what a perfect
seat thanks
i have to earn a better one you guys you
got to work your way up to the court's
chairs you know okay so
let's let's let's talk business
mumbo said that he wanted to make this
gigantic shop and i heard down the
grapevine that you also wanted to create
a gigantic shop so you know maybe
maybe we create an even gigantic shop
you know a gigantic shop sounds amazing
i mean this is something i've been
wanting to do for so long i mean we if
someone's got to stop concorp
they've got a monopoly it's it's not
good
we've decided that we're calling it
sahara because obviously we can't call
it amazon so we're calling it the sahara
you know amazon rainforest sahara desert
now people have been telling me like
amazon is called amazon because of you
know all the it's like a to z and it's
got loads of stuff in it but
i feel like we can call it sahara and
just make sure we sell a lot of sand so
do you have any
sort of
sketching anything that you've done i
mean if we built the gt base you and i
pretty much i mean others helped but we
built the foundation and we built it off
of a toilet sketch that you'd made i
have produced another sketch are you
ready for this are you ready for the big
reveal
it's not complete
and it's not it's not finished yet it
needs another artist touch but boom
there wow okay boom okay
i knew i could trust you for these
weird sketches so why don't we head on
over there and see like lay out some of
this and maybe even get started on it
i yes yeah i can't wait let's let's go
as you can see i've already flattened
all of this world or this area so it's
basically ready to go more or less can
you see where it's all
like yeah it sort of makes it sort of
makes a lot of sense now looking at the
drawing again i mean it's still a very
weird green drawing okay so i guess
let's
let's get on the grind
let's get some blocks and start
building this toilet
okay so let's kick off this time lapse
by saying yes i forgot to press f1 but
then iskal reminded me to hit f1 so i
did
and now it is free of the chat so thank
you iskal for not only telling me to f1
but for helping me
start off the project so we have been
making this gigantic rectangle of light
gray concrete now we did this in powder
because
we did exactly the same thing that i did
to my base and we saved ourselves a lot
of grinding time by making it out of
powder and then we pour water all over
the top but not using buckets but with
ice and it kept freezing over and it
made it a lot quicker to do so once we
had this it was going to be
our place to put our logo on but we had
a huge amount of problems trying to get
one that looked good as you can see look
at this it didn't look right the s was
wrong the spacing was wrong so we
decided to take the whole thing down
and try in again in the kind of small
font until we absolutely nailed it and
then moved it into the top left hand
corner and then it was time to actually
start on the main building so that
gigantic thing that took us two hours to
build was simply so that we could write
the name of the company
which is yeah i think that's pretty
telling of
how epic this project is going to be and
how time-consuming it's going we are
going all out on this and we are
planning on selling just about
everything but we're making sure that
we've got a lot of sand as well so we've
got a few reference pictures that we're
working off of but for the most part we
have no idea where this is going and
we're improving it and just trying to
play around and get the right kind of
shapes but you have to see that this is
a couple hundred blocks long and you
need so many resources for this so
unfortunately we ran out now after that
hefty hefty time lapse
you can see
that we have done a lot it took us a
long time to get this logo down as you
could probably see but i think it's been
absolutely nailed now this obviously is
one gigantic bit of gray concrete light
gray concrete but i think it will end up
being a bit more decorated when we're
finished obviously we have not even half
a shell completed and this was stacks
and stacks and stacks of concrete
absolutely ridiculous we ran out of sand
we ran out of gravel and we've had to go
back to the grind however hopefully
you can see how this is all shaping up
it's obviously in a kind of similar
style with the whole palette but it is
slightly different this is one major
headquarters
being built right here the hermitcraft
rail network is actually going to go
straight under here and through because
it basically cuts right through the
building and you should be able to see
at least something from inside the glass
tunnel however there's still a lot of
work to be done here so i think maybe
next episode we're going to time lapse
again to try and get the majority of
this done now i've been thinking about
some of the rooms that need to go inside
here we're going to need a meeting room
we're going to need like a news room
we're going to need we're going to need
some planning quarters we're going to
need storage like the whole shebang the
basically the difference between the g
team base and the sahara project is that
this is a force
to make money and the other one was a
force to win a war so quite different in
essence however i feel like this is
twice as big and it's going to be twice
as impressive but i think that's all
we're going to actually have time for
when it comes to the sahara project
because there are so many things going
on at the moment i have indeed got
another side project that we need to
whoa
i've gone completely i've gone dark
what the heck
it's like someone turned the lights out
on me
this is weird
huh
i am going as i said to become sherlock
green and in order to do that
i need to make
2 2 1 g not b 2 2 1 g baker street
and i obviously started that last
episode over there by the duke statue
i've now completed it as you can see
it's popping over the top there now i
have made a small time lapse to show
that again i know there's a lot of
there's a lot of time lapsing going on
in this episode but i've just been so
busy doing things so let's get into it
now this time lapse didn't take nearly
as long as the other one now what i did
last episode was i started this and i
got the foundations down and i thought i
could put it there because it was a nice
convenient location
now i then realized the building was
going to be way too big and i asked duke
if i could move it and he said yes i
could even move the statue and i thought
no i'm definitely not going to do that
so i'm going to shift the whole thing
over so i ripped down what i did and
moved it over all the way to the right
of the mumbo statue so it doesn't
interfere i did cover it up quite badly
as you'll see later but i decided that i
was going to build this house in the
actual style of real life baker street
now unfortunately in minecraft we don't
have the specific kind of blocks you
would need in order to do that so i went
for sandstone and brick very realistic
street kind of thing i did a tutorial on
this a long time ago so i was able to
sort of replicate exactly what i did
back then and just make one little
townhouse on the side of it and i think
it actually fits in quite nicely added a
couple of chimneys a nice dormer at the
top and i think this will actually fit
in quite nicely i think it's actually
one of the better shops in the shopping
district and we have the final product
right in front of you if this doesn't
remind you of a certain downtown evo i
don't know what will it's basically very
very similar it's just a style that i
really enjoy i think it fits quite
nicely into the shopping district and
yes of course as i mentioned in the time
lapse itself i have moved it that is a
very ugly mound that i've created but i
plan on fixing that a little later on
basically because there's going to be a
building there
i think i'll uh i'll probably be
terraforming this anyway i just wanted
to cover up the mess that i made um but
yeah this looks absolutely fantastic i
obviously still need to make a bridge
over here
and actually make the inside i need well
it's basically just an office i need to
just make a desk so i need to clear and
hollow all of this out in order to be
able to do that and i've got all sorts
of mysteries to solve now there's quite
a few mysteries out there on the
hermitcraft server as we very well know
and before sherlock green makes his
first appearance we're gonna have to
make sure that his office is created but
let's just go over some of the mysteries
we have who is
the jingler i mean the jingler hasn't
been seen for quite some time which you
know leads me to believe it's one of the
hermits that has no longer been
uploading hermitcraft but it could all
be a ruse who knows we have who is the
salmon man or the salmon ghost or
whatever
the weird salmon thing is we need to get
to the bottom of that
asap because
he's making appearances now but
we don't know what his end goal is and
then of course the ultimate question
who is
poultry man
nobody knows obviously he's gone into
retirement
uh because of the war but the war is
over now maybe you know on some beach
a million miles away he's gonna get a
postcard saying the war's over and he'll
come back
to perform his
feathered justice
but of course it's not just our own
personal mysteries that we need to solve
we need clients and whatever mysteries
they need solving that is what we're
after and hopefully to make a few
diamonds at the same time i i can't
emphasize enough how we are definitely
one of the poorest hermits on the server
and this is from the man that got gifted
three stacks of diamond blocks and it is
all hollowed out now obviously there's
um quite a lot of missing walls and such
so there's still quite a bit of interior
work to do here and you know what i've
i've just realized something we've been
playing on hermitcraft now for what
eight months eight whole months if
you've been watching for eight whole
months
well thank you for a start but hear me
out i don't think i've done any interior
this entire season
honestly if you think about it the gteam
base didn't really have any major
interior my base hasn't got a single bit
of real interior when it comes to just
making a room
this is probably the first project
which is absolutely insane considering
how long we've been playing on the
server but i'm afraid that is all we
have time for today everybody i am sorry
but before i go i need to show you
what sherlock green looks like here here
i am
ready to solve some mysteries
you know i don't think the eyebrows
quite work on me but it does have that
like hmm
interesting
it has that effect which i quite like so
basically after this is done
sherlock grien will be on the case and i
think we can finally christen this 2 2 1
g
baker street i think that's got a really
nice ring to it and it fits in perfectly
so all i've got to do now is work on
this interior it doesn't need to be
anything special because you know this
is just the office this is just where
the business is conducted
and then the real mysteries
are on and if you guys know of any
mysteries that really need solving you
got to let me know in the in the
comments below obviously i know about
poultry man biggest mystery of the
entire series if you ask me we know
about salmon man who
who the heck is that what is that and we
know about the jingler who hasn't been
seen in a while so maybe no one cares
about that mystery but what else is
going on that needs solving oh my god i
got it i love this skin anyway that is
all that we have time for everyone so
thank you very much for watching today's
rather busy and epic episode and i shall
see you next time goodbye